the second half of the year should be
quite positive and that Bitcoin could
reach we benchmark Bitcoin against gold
specifically the 50% of the gold market
that is more speculative in nature if
Bitcoin can reach the 50% of gold that's
speculative in nature that would imply
and over the longer term we think
there's a good chance that central banks
and sovereign wealth funds will start to
get more aggressive in adopting Bitcoin
in that scenario where Bitcoin
denominated trade could be say 5% of
global trade we get to
We have not really seen the same
curiosity or bullishness on some of the
altcoins. A lot of that comes down to
it's definitely a bare market in the
altcoins. You think that's going to
change? I think it if we got a big rally
up to 107K, let's say, so short of the
all-time high and it was accompanied by
a lot a lot of froth in the market that
we would identify as topping signals.
That would be uh probably pretty
bearish. Would you say you're still
bullish on Ethereum long term?
[Music]
We're getting the outlook for Bitcoin
and the larger crypto landscape with our
next guest, Matthew Seagull. He's a head
of digital asset research at Venet. Good
to see you again, Matthew. Welcome back.
I'm David Lynn. I'm Bonnie. Um, people
love your Bitcoin price prediction. Can
you tell us your prediction short-term,
long-term, uh maybe 2025 and 2026?
Sure. Uh yeah, we've been really
encouraged by the interest from the
traditional asset management community
into Bitcoin ETFs, especially since the
election. Uh my inbound phone calls are
up like 300%. from investment advisors
who were afraid to allocate to Bitcoin
ETFs and now with the election and the
change in administration, they're much
more open to discussing uh the
investment case for Bitcoin. So this is
obviously a very volatile asset and so
we look at the short term tends to be
driven by macro
considerations, liquidity trends and
technicals. So assuming that Bitcoin can
get through this period of uncertainty,
which we think is macro driven, interest
rates come down, the Fed gets a little
easier, we think the second half of the
year should be quite positive and that
Bitcoin could reach 180,000 per coin.
That's based on an analysis of previous
Bitcoin cycles which have tended to get
smaller over time. But the previous
smallest Bitcoin cycle was a 20x return
from the trough to the peak. If we can
do a 10x return this cycle, that would
imply 180K. So that's kind of our
guidepost for this year. Uh again,
liquidity and technicals could change
that, but that's my base case is 180 for
this year. For those advisers taking a
longer term perspective, we benchmark
Bitcoin against gold. Specifically, the
50% of the gold market that is more
speculative in nature. So about half of
gold goes into jewelry or industrial use
cases. Put putting that aside, if
Bitcoin can reach the 50% of gold that's
speculative in nature, that would imply
roughly 450,000 per coin. So I know a
lot of folks are calling it for that
this year. that would mark a break in
that cycle. You know, each cycle gets
smaller for Bitcoin. So, I have a hard
time calling that for this cycle, but
that could be maybe a 20 27 2028 450 per
coin. And then over the longer term, we
think there's a good chance that central
banks and sovereign wealth funds will
start to get more aggressive in adopting
Bitcoin, not only as a store of value,
but also as a medium exchange. So this
year the Czech Republic, the governor of
the central bank there has initiated a
study to analyze Bitcoin for inclusion
in their central bank reserves. And then
just this week, Russia did a trade with
China uh partially denominated in
Bitcoin, beginning to really use Bitcoin
for the first time as a medium of
exchange. And that's not for individuals
buying coffee. That's for largecale
transactions where countries are using
Bitcoin as an intermediary currency to
do say an oil trade. And in that
scenario where Bitcoin denominated trade
could be say 5% of global trade. We get
to a $3 million price per Bitcoin.
That's a long-term prediction like 2050.
Uh but that's going to be necessary, we
think, to elevate Bitcoin into the
millions per coin. You said we want to
get to 5%. Where are we now? Zero.
Right. So basically like nobody is using
Bitcoin in global trade. There's a small
amount of remittances that are going on.
But think of that as a gift where one
person is just sending value to another.
But uh to do something where you're
trading oil but using Bitcoin as the
intermediary currency, there's basically
none of that going on. So I think this
week's action by Russia is kind of a
zero to one moment uh in terms of uh
launching Bitcoin as a as a medium of
exchange. Um that's because Bitcoin is
very easy for people to understand. It's
digital gold. But what about Ethereum
and Solana? They have ETFs. Do people
understand them? How are they
performing?
Yeah.
Um, in contrast to those inbound phone
calls from advisers who want to talk
about Bitcoin, we have not really seen
the same um, curiosity or bullishness on
some of the altcoins. Uh, I think a lot
of that comes down to performance. Uh,
they've been underperforming. Uh,
another part is related to the use case.
Uh, so um, much of it is kind of
speculative in nature. We haven't really
seen the transmission mechanism whereby
say stable stablecoin aum starts to
generate meaningful fees for say
Ethereum token holders or salana token
holders. I think some of that um is
still ahead of us as deregulation kicks
off in the US. It's actually pretty hard
to say buy Salana based USDC if you're
here in New York State. the regulator
just makes it very difficult. So, as
that as those regulations ease, you
know, we're optimistic that some of
those real world use cases can kick off,
but right now with the over supply in
tokens, with meme coins kind of sucking
up some of the liquidity, uh it's
definitely a bare market in the
altcoins. You think that's going to
change? I think it will once a
significant quantum of Bitcoin wealth
has been created. So the history of the
asset class is once Bitcoin can kind of
pump 30 to 50% then a lot of those gains
get recycled into newer projects uh
there's just been too many uh newer
projects and Bitcoin's down well flat
year to date. Um so I I do think you
when these ETFs come to market when
staking is permitted when you can um
create and redeem these ETFs using inind
so the coins themselves not just cash
that means every broker dealer in the US
is going to be need to touching crypto
directly that means that they're more
likely to hold some for working capital
purposes and the coins that maybe have
lower inflation rates you know could see
good performance.
Yeah, you talked about the crypto bull
cycle this year going back to markets uh
in your one of your recent reports peak
in Q1 um setting new highs in Q4 uh 30%
retracement in BTC. Is that what's
happening right now? The 30%
retracement. Is that the period we're in
right now? I think it is. Okay. So,
we've already hit the peak in Q1. Is
that kind of the rationale? Yeah. I mean
our original our initial idea was that
the inauguration would prompt a blowoff
top to say 125 then the reality would
set in governing is hard deregulation is
hard there's many entrenched interests
that will fight against it and you'd
have a draw down in kind of Q2 Q3 before
a subsequent rally so we never hit that
125k instead we just got the draw down I
think we should remember in 2021
um there was a 54% Bitcoin draw down
from the March peak uh until the October
peak. So, it feels like we're in a
period kind of like that. Uh you talked
about a Bitcoin strategic reserve in
this um report. This was written before
Trump announced a crypto strategic
reserve that was signed into executive
action a couple weeks ago. How does that
change the calculus for your forecast
for uh some of the larger layer ones?
I think it's in line with our
expectations. Uh the US government is
very unlikely to acquire altcoins in the
open market. My reading of the executive
order is that it allows for the
government to hold on to whatever
altcoins may be seized, but it also
gives them the freedom to sell them if
they want. We could have a scenario
where the government is selling altcoins
and buying bitcoin because the strategic
reserve for bitcoin explicitly
uh lays out a scenario where the
government is acquiring bitcoin in the
open market albeit in a revenuene
neutral model. So maybe that means
selling alts and and buying bitcoin. Um
but I don't I I wouldn't say that we've
become more bullish on alts because of
the uh stockpile that was announced.
Would you be more bearish because they
can now sell a big amount?
Um, government doesn't own too many
altcoins. So, I don't think that I mean
it symbolically it might be negative if
they were to sell them. I don't think it
would mean too much for supply demand.
And you know, many of these tokens are
down 50 60%. Uh, so at this point
riskreward feels to me more bullish than
bearish. So earlier you mentioned the
crypto waterfall where Bitcoin rallies
first and then small caps. So that in
the crypto community is the four-year
cycle. So a lot of people do not believe
in four-year cycle. I would assume that
you believe
it. Uh I believe it but I'm willing to
change my mind if it doesn't play out
right. If 2025 is a down year for
Bitcoin, that would probably invalidate
the four-year cycle and prompt me to
rethink it. It's not the only variable,
but it's one piece of the matrix that I
do tend to trust uh until proven
otherwise. I hope it happens.
Well, let's talk about some Bitcoin
companies or crypto companies overall
that you like. What are some of the um
bull cases for holding on to a crypto
company versus just the layer 1 itself?
Yeah. Um, so we've actually uh been
doing a lot more work in the equity
space this year. Uh, part of the reason
for that is that we saw that the 2024
vintage of altcoins was not designed
particularly well. They were either meme
coins with no utility and no pass
through or they were kind of layer 2s
with a lot of inflation and no logical
buyer. Um, in contrast, the equity
universe uh just doesn't have the same
amount of inflation, right? Um, so if
you look at the available supply of
equities that are geared to Bitcoin and
digital assets right now, it's roughly
$200 billion of stocks. A lot of that is
Coinbase, Micro Strategy, and then the
Bitcoin miners. And there are a number
of IPOs that we're expecting this year.
Some of them are here in this room. I
saw Gemini for example with a booth. But
even if you to add up all of the market
cap of those companies that might come
public this year, it's maybe 20 billion.
So 20 billion on a base of 200 billion.
It's not a huge amount of supply. As
long as these companies are profitable,
we think that they could have, you know,
some valuation support. Uh and we've
seen the performance of companies that
just add a little bit of Bitcoin to
their balance sheet. Sometimes the best
performing stocks are not the pure
plays. They're the companies that have
say 1% exposure to crypto and it's going
to 5%. You know, and Robin Hood would be
a good example of a company like that.
Their crypto exposure a couple years ago
was Dominus. Now it's almost 30% of the
business and Robin Hood's been able to
use that uh kind of innovation on
digital assets to capture other
customers and it's helping their
multiple u. So, we've been doing a lot
more work uh among those what I'd call
tradi enablers um traditional
institutions that are getting more
aggressive to embrace the innovator's
dilemma rather than push against it and
you should see some more funds from us
in that space uh over the next quarter.
Did you say small percentage of Bitcoin
like all the companies doing that
performs better than companies that have
a huge amount of Bitcoin on their
balance sheet?
I guess what I'm saying is that um when
a company kind of goes from zero to one,
that can move the needle a lot on how
the market perceives them and what type
of multiple they're willing to pay for
the stock without introducing a ton of
additional volatility. Whereas some of
these Bitcoin miners, for example, they
are already pure plays in Bitcoin. Then
they go and borrow money to add more
Bitcoin to their balance sheet. that
makes them extremely volatile and the
market often doesn't pay a huge uh
multiple on the earnings, right? So,
we're thinking to broaden the investment
universe away from just the say 20 pure
plays to include the hundred or so
companies that are doing something with
digital assets. The back testing shows
much better performance at the portfolio
level. Could you share your outlook of
2025 and 2026? Are we heading into a
recession? Everyone's worried about the
tariffs. What's happening? Yeah. Uh this
is a digestion period for macro
observers. Uh the uncertainty around the
administration's approach to tariffs
caused a pull forward of economic
activity. So lots of companies bought
goods from overseas in
Q4 before the tariffs would go into
effect. And as a result, kind of Q4 GDP
was overstated and there's a bit of an
air pocket in Q1 GDP. And as the market
woke up to that, GDP estimates fell,
earnings estimates fell, and US,
specifically US tech has started to
underperform dramatically the rest of
the markets. And because Bitcoin and
other digital assets have been
reasonably highly correlated to US tech,
they got hit as well. Our reading of
some of the sentiment indicators shows
that last week there really were some
kind of peak fear indicators in the
market. And so we're optimistic that
there'll be a rebound in Q2. The market
will get more certainty around the
tariffs. And this was more of a one-time
than a persistent negative impact on GDP
because even if we get tariffs, there's
going to be a deregulation
um uh agenda out of this administration.
there's going to be tax cuts. The second
half of the year looks a lot better from
our perspective. So, still pretty
bullish, maybe more even equity
performance where US tech is not such an
outperformer. Uh but given that
Bitcoin's correlation with tech has
fallen quite a bit compared to 2022, I
think there's a reasonable chance for a
decoupling, still sticking with Bitcoin
180 uh in Q4 this year. What about
equity market though? Um earlier you
said people already start buying goods
Q4 last year and does that mean it's
priced in. Well, they stockpiled
inventories in Q4 to make to to not have
to pay tariffs that would come into
effect in Q8. So they knew. Yeah, they
expected it. They knew. Trump said it on
the campaign trail many times. But those
inventories are not going to last them
for two years, right? They might last
for two quarters. People will be back in
the market. the tariffs will be a
one-time hit. Sentiment will come back
as the tax cuts get passed hopefully mid
year uh and the second half should be
better. You have an interesting panel at
this conference. It's entitled building
empirical valuation frameworks for
digital assets. This is an interesting
topic because we think about let's say
Bitcoin for example. People think it's
digital gold. Gold is a commodity.
There's no DCF. There's no discounted
cash flow you can use to value gold.
There's no DCF to value Bitcoin. How do
you know if Bitcoin or any other layer 1
is fairly valued at any given point?
Yeah, I mean so for Bitcoin the
empirical model is a comparative one and
I think that um your observation is
correct that there's no discounted cash
flow model you can build. It's all based
on what its perceived value. um that's
different from from from some of the
proofofstake networks like Ethereum and
Salana where the level of complexity in
the transactions is much higher. Uh you
can build these logical loops if A then
B and users have proven that they're
willing to pay for those transactions
and the fees that users pay end up in
the token holders pocket in some way or
another. Whereas for Bitcoin, the fees
that users pay end up in the Bitcoin
miner valuation, right? So you can build
DCFs for some of these layer 1 tokens. U
I don't think that they have much
predictive ability as to how the token
trades. Um you know, this is retail
driven market uh driven by flows and
sentiment and vibe. uh but for kind of
longer term investors, these DCFs can
DCFS, discounted cash flow models can at
least establish uh some um kind of
scenario analysis. What type of fees
would have to be uh paid on the
blockchain over what time period to
justify the price of the asset. When I
when I was in college, I had a finance
class and one of my props asked us, "If
we were to recreate dinosaurs, and
dinosaurs were to be born again, like
Jurassic Park, how much would you buy a
dinosaur for?" Right? I think that
basis, the question is, it's a
completely new asset that no one's ever
seen before. How do we know how much to
pay for it? And when cryptos first hit
the mainstream media, I think that was
kind of the sentiment. No one knew what
Salana was. is it's like how do we know,
you know, how do we know how much to pay
for it? How do you approach a new coin
or a new layer 1 that just enters the
market? Uh yeah, we typically won't buy
most new coins in most layer ones that
enter the market. We're not we're
passing on 99.9% of tokens. We're
looking for doxed teams. So you know not
anonymous teams but great docs teams
building products that are better than
the tradfi analog where there's some
value capture mechanism in the token uh
where the fees that user pays can end up
in the pockets of token holders and that
shrinks the investable universe
dramatically. Uh and then we also find
that a lot of tokens come to market just
too expensive compared to those trady
analoges. So, we'd like to watch the
token as it comes to market. Typically
may have some pump driven by retail
interest that marks a top and then the
token goes down 90% and we're looking to
buy it when it's in that trough of
disillusionment uh where the valuation
is much lower. But in the end, it is the
discounted cash flows which should form
the bedrock of a token's value. I know
Bonnie and many other people in the
space were disappointed at Ethereum this
year
because of the model earlier you said
the capturing of revenue Ethereum is not
really doing that now because they are
sharing the revenue with their L2s right
and we are hoping that it's going to
change your thoughts uh I agree with
that diagnosis
um sometimes when you're trying to uh
seed an ecosystem. Uh it helps to be
generous and I think that's kind of the
approach that the Ethereum Foundation
has taken with the L2s is that they want
to get as many out there as possible to
try to find product market fit. Uh it
hasn't been tremendous that some of
these L2s are accepting stable coins as
gas, right? You really want to see the
Ethereum ecosystem aligned whereby ETH
is the unit of account and ETH is used
for gas. And I think the the governance
um of the Ethereum and and the Ethereum
Foundation is kind of recognizing this
in their own uh decentralized fashion
and we will see a more Ethereum aligned
ecosystem of L2s over the next couple
years. Uh and maybe that will
reinvigorate the token price. Would you
say you're still bullish on Ethereum
long term? Bullish. Yes.
Uh maybe our position sizes are smaller
than they used to be and some of that
has been through performance. Uh and you
know I do want to see the um Ethereum
Foundation and the key opinion leaders
in Ethereum be more vocal about why the
token is good. Right? We often say it on
our team the token is the product. uh it
sounds crass but this is you know retail
driven market and you have to make the
case that your token is great and maybe
people were you know too proud to do
that or I don't know the reason but it
seems like there are some changes uh in
how those leaders are approaching the
token um somebody said the global
financial system will be built on
Ethereum and they're looking forward to
a 247
um equity market maybe
onchain. What is your thought?
Um well, if you look at the stable coin
issuers, they very few of them are on
one chain, right? They're on lots of
different chains and those stable coin
issuers almost become the bridge between
lots of L1's. Uh so I do agree that
Ethereum has kind of the most traction
in the banking system, many of whom have
forked Ethereum or who are experimenting
on the open- source blockchains. Uh but
I think it's going to be a multi-chain
world. Uh, and I think one thing that we
should be on the lookout for from this
SEC are some noa action letters that
might allow tokenized equities to trade
on decentralized exchanges without a
broker dealer license. That would be a
big deal. Uh, I think that Hester Pierce
wants to see that from an ideological
perspective. Uh but you'll know it
before it happens because they will
issue some no action letters giving
these exchanges kind of permission to go
ahead and try it. How soon will we see
that you think? Um maybe by the end of
the year.
Uh but there's a lot of steps to get to.
So Hester Pierce three weeks ago put out
a list of 50 questions for the industry
to answer and a lot of them are around
custody and staking and what it means to
be a broker dealer in the space. And
those questions are still being
answered. They're really detailed. And I
know from sitting on some advisory
committees of industry associations that
the answers are still being collated,
have not even been submitted to the SEC
yet. Uh and I think that's why the SEC
delayed the approval of uh in kind
creation redemption for some of these
ETFs. Uh have pushed the approval of
some of the altcoin ETFs is we got to
get these questions answered first and
it's going to take a couple
quarters. My final question and then
maybe Bunny has another one. What would
derail your bullish crypto outlook for
2025 2026? What macro events would need
to happen for you to say we're not
hitting new all-time highs anymore?
Um, well, if we got a big rally up to
107K, let's say, so short of the
all-time high, and it was accompanied by
a lot a lot of froth in the market that
we would identify as topping signals,
say like Coinbase or Phantom app
downloads and funding rates in DeFi
spiking, um, like very high unrealized
profits in Bitcoin, but we failed to
make new all-time highs. That would be
uh probably pretty bearish. Uh I guess
another one would be a reaceleration in
inflation. Uh that might compromise like
um kind of risk assets generally
probably those two things.
If
you were
30year-old have 100k sitting on the
sideline, how would you invest now?
um a 30year-old. Okay, so this is not
investment advice. Uh but I would
probably put like 85 or 90%
into stocks, um index funds or whatever
high conviction equities and then 10 or
15% into Bitcoin and digital assets and
Bitcoin would probably be you know 3/4
of that. uh and I would spread out my
purchases because this is a very
volatile asset. So, it's helpful to buy,
you know, a little bit every day or a
little bit every week rather than trying
to pick a bottom, you know, with one big
trade. You know what they say, um if you
try to pick bottoms, you end up with
smelly fingers or whatever they say. So,
uh that would be my advice. That was
great. Excellent. Thank you very much,
Maddie. I appreciate you joining us.
Thank you, Bonnie.